Guide to the Chard Powers Smith Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Chard Powers Smith papers
1759-1978
1910-1977
YCAL MSS 324
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
92.5
(225 boxes)
The papers contain writings, correspondence, personal papers, photographs, and family papers of twentieth-century American writer Chard Powers Smith. The collection documents his career through drafts of his writings and through correspondence that reveals his personal and professional relationships with fellow writers, publishers, and literary organizations. The papers also contain information about his family, documenting not only his relationships with family members but also the lives of his parents and grandparents in nineteenth-century Watertown, New York. Smith's experiences during World War I and his travels in Europe in the 1920s are documented through correspondence, autobiographical writings, photographs, and scrapbooks. His involvement with the Distributist and Agrarian movements of the 1930s is evidenced by correspondence, writings, and printed ephemera, and the collection also documents his involvement with the Society of Friends, or Quakers, particularly from the 1950s through the end of his life.
Smith, Chard Powers, 1894-1977
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Chard Powers Smith and Eunice Clark Smith, 1950-1989.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Cold Storage (Photographic negatives): Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Chard Powers Smith (1894-1977)
The writer Chard Powers Smith was born in Watertown, New York, and educated at the Pawling School and Yale University, class of 1916. Following service as a captain in the U.S. Army Field Artillery during World War I, he received a law degree from Harvard in 1921, but early abandoned the practice of law to make his living as a writer. A regular at the MacDowell Colony in Peterborough, New Hampshire, throughout his career, he published in a variety of genres. His best known works include Artillery of Time, a historical novel; Where the Light Falls, a biography/memoir of the poet Edwin Arlington Robinson; and The Housatonic: Puritan River, part of the Rivers of America series.
Smith was born into comfortable circumstances in upstate New York, his parents' marriage having joined two of Watertown's most prominent families. His father, Edward North Smith, practiced law in partnership with his father, and was later a Justice of the New York Supreme Court, Fifth District. His mother, Alice Lamon Powers, the daughter of a wealthy businessman, died in childbirth when Smith was eleven. Smith maintained a home in an old mill in nearby Sackets Harbor for many years, and based much of his writing on family and local history.
Like many writers of his generation, Smith traveled and lived in Europe intermittently in the 1920s, and moved in American expatriate social and literary circles. He studied at Oxford in 1921, and in that year also married Olive Cary Macdonald; she died of complications from pregnancy in 1924 while the two were living in Italy. In addition to inspiring his own volume of poetry, Along the Wind, Smith's first marriage was purported to be a source for Ernest Hemingway's short story "Mr. and Mrs. Elliot;" Smith maintained a bitter grudge about the story all his life.
In 1929 Smith married Marion Antoinette ("Nanette") Chester. The couple lived in Connecticut and had two children, Chard Powers Smith, Jr., and Marion Kendall Smith. Smith and his second wife divorced in 1957, and in the same year he married Eunice Waters Clark, a professor of French. After spending the last two decades of his life in Arlington, Vermont, Smith died in a nursing home in Williamstown, Massachusetts, in 1977.
Family Tree
Leonard Powers (1795-1884) m.1815 Diadema Caldwell
--Diadema Powers m.1845 Salmasius Bordwell
--Isaac Proctor Powers ("Ike" ) (1826-1908) m.1858 Lorinda Lamon (circa 1838-1921)
----Charles Lamon Powers (1870-1871)
----Alice Lamon Powers Smith (1872-1906)
Savillian Smith (b.1807) m.1836 Louisa Chafee
--Hannibal Smith (1839-1899) m.1866 Amelia Marsh
----Edward North Smith (1868-1943)
----William Hannibal Smith
----Elizabeth Chard Smith m. Frank Gallup
----Amelia Lydia Smith
----Eli Marsh Smith
Edward North Smith m.1894 Alice Lamon Powers; m.1923 Marion Ward
--Chard Powers Smith (1894-1977)
.......m.1921 Olive Cary Macdonald (circa 1888-1924)
.......m.1929 Marion Antoinette Chester ("Nanette"); divorced 1957
------------Chard Powers Smith, Jr. ("Cepe") (born 1931) m.1953 Mary Elizabeth Carey ("Dusty")
----------------------Arthur Tremaine Smith ("Trem")
----------------------Carey Smith
----------------------Sarah Smith
------------Marion Kendall Smith ("Kendall") m.1959 William Clinton Stanley
-----------------------Eamon Stanley
-----------------------Sam Stanley
.......m.1957 Eunice Waters Clark
Sources of information include: Monroe, Joel H. Through Eleven Decades of History: Watertown, a History from 1800 to 1912 with Illustrations and Many Incidents (Watertown: Hungerford-Holbrook Co., 1912), and Haddock, John A. The Growth of a Century: as Illustrated in the History of Jefferson County, New York, from 1793-1894 (Philadelphia: Sherman & Co., 1894).
Scope and Contents
The papers contain writings, correspondence, personal papers, photographs, and family papers of twentieth-century American writer Chard Powers Smith, who wrote in several genres including poetry, historical fiction, and literary analysis. The collection documents his career through drafts of his writings and through correspondence that reveals his personal and professional relationships with fellow writers, publishers, and literary organizations. The papers also contain information about his family, documenting not only his relationships with family members but also the lives of his parents and grandparents in nineteenth-century Watertown, New York. Smith's experiences during World War I and his travels in Europe in the 1920s are documented through correspondence, autobiographical writings, photographs, and scrapbooks. His involvement in the Distributist and Agrarian movements of the 1930s is evidenced by correspondence, writings, and printed ephemera, and the collection also documents his involvement with the Society of Friends, or Quakers, particularly from the 1950s through the end of his life.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Correspondence (1901-1978). II. Writings (circa 1922-1956, undated). III. Personal Papers (1759-1977). IV. Family Papers (1852-1965, undated). V. Subject Files and Printed Material (circa 1920s-1960s). VI. Photographs (circa 1870s-1960s).
Free America; Agrarians (Group of writers); Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Individualism -- United States; Quakers -- United States -- 20th Century; World War, 1914-1918; Watertown (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Baker, Carlos, 1909-1987; Borsodi, Ralph, 1888-1977; Cohen, Rose, 1880-1925; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961; Powers, Isaac Proctor, 1826-1908; Powers, Lorinda Lamon, ca. 1838-1921; Robinson, Edwin Arlington, 1869-1935; Rorty, James, 1890-1973; Smith, Alice Lamon Powers, 1872-1906; Smith, Chard Powers, 1894-1977; Smith, Edward North, 1868-1943; Smith, Eunice Clark; Smith, Hannibal, 1839-1899; Smith, Marion Antoinette; Smith, Olive Cary Macdonald, ca.1888-1924; Szold-Fritz, Bernardine; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972; MacDowell Colony (Peterborough, N.H.)
- Correspondence, 1901-1978; Series I; 21.27; (51 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I. Correspondence is organized into four subseries: General Correspondence, Family Correspondence, Third Party Correspondence and Correspondence Photocopies. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents
  General Correspondence contains Chard Powers Smith's correspondence spanning 1910-1978. Carbon copies and drafts of outgoing letters are interfiled with incoming correspondence, and in some cases files contain only outgoing letters. Smith's correspondence documents his personal and professional relationships throughout his life. Of interest among his literary correspondence is a file of acrimonious letters to and from Hemingway concerning Smith's reaction to the story "Mr. and Mrs. Elliot"; this matter is further documented in correspondence with the biographer Carlos Baker, who obtained Smith's copies of the letters. Some of the larger files in the subseries include professional exchanges with editors and publishers, and personal correspondence with friends such as James Rorty, Mark Van Doren, Bernardine Szold, and Rose Gollup Cohen. Also present is a substantial file documenting Smith's involvement, along with Ralph Borsodi and others, in an effort to unite the Distributist and Agrarian movements, and his his co-editorship of the periodical Free America; this correspondence is filed together under the heading Distributist-Agrarian Movement. An extensive file concerning the Friends Seminary in New York City also documents Smith's involvement with the Albany Friends Meeting.
  The Family Correspondence subseries contains correspondence between Chard Powers Smith and members of his family, spanning the years 1901 to 1977. The files of letters home to his parents and grandmother are extensive and give details about his experiences at the Pawling School, at Yale, in World War I, and in Europe after the war, while other letters document his relationships with his wives, children, grandchildren, and extended family. Additional family correspondence can be found in Series IV. Family Papers.
  Third Party Correspondence contains letters to and from other parties, spanning the years 1919-1973. Correspondence Photocopies duplicates a small portion of the general correspondence, and may be related to Smith's work on his autobiography.
  - General Correspondence, 1910-1978
    - "A" General, 1935-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A. M. Heath & Co., 1928-1960, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Abbot Press, 1935 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Abrams, Al, 1973 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Accent: a quarterly of the new literature, 1940 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ackerson, Dean, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Adams, Ted and Rezsin, 1964-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Agar, Herbert, 1937, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Free America
    - Agard, Robert, 1972 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Agence Hoffman, 1958 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Agnew, Charles D. Jr, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Aiken, George D., 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Akeley, Carl Ethan, 1925 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Akeley, Delia J. (Delia Julia), 1927 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Albany. Traffic Court, 1963 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Alexander, Elizabeth, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Aley, Maxwell, 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Aley, Ruth, 1935 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Allan Swallow Publisher, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Alland, Alexander, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1930-1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      See also: Farrar & Rinehart, Inc.
    - Allen, Mildred, 1951 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Allen, Robert F., 1973 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Allen, Tommie and Ellwood, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Allied Publishers Limited, 1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Alpert, Hollis, 1952 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Alsop, Rupert Kelso, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Amberg, E. J., 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      See also: Connecticut Light & Power Co.
    - America National Catholic Weekly, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - American Antiquarian Society, 1948 October (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1951 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - American International College, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - American Literature, 1960 August (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - American Mercury, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - American Museum of Natural History, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      General note
      Includes: Gregory, William R.
    - American Scholar, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      Includes: Thompson, Homer A.
    - Amherst College, 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Ami, H. M., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Anderson, Henry Hill, 1935 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Anderson, Jacky, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Anderson, John W., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Anderson, Marcella, 1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Anderson, Maxwell, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Anderson, T. M., 1928 Jun 15 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Anderson, Wallace L., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Andrews, Edward D., 1942 December 29 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Andrews, Julia M., 1946 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Angell, Agatha, 1933 November 17 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Annie Laurie Williams, Inc., 1939-1960 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Antioch Press, 1961, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1958, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Arens, R. W., 1941 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Arlington Memorial School, 1966 May 13 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Arliss, George, 1931 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Arnold, Katherine, 1962 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Atheneum (New York, N.Y.), 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Atkinson, Mary, 1935 October 16 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1920, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Atwell, Gladys, 1940 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Auclair, Jean-Louis, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Aufbau Reconstruction, 1950 March 2 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Authors' Guild (U.S.), 1939 November (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - "B" General, 1928-1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Backus, Louse Laidlow, 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Bader, Andy, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Baker, Carlos, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Baker, George P., 1923 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Balassa, Alia, 1974, undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Ballard, William and Elizabeth, 1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Ballantine Books (Firm), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Barati, George, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Barerdsi, Gig, undated (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Barger, Mark, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Barker, Melanie, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Barnard College, 1949 May 23 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Barnard, Dorothy, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Barnard, Ellsworth, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Barnette, Dorothy, 1939 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Barnum, William Henry, 1946 July 31 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Baroda Community Development Service, 1970 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Barr, Ellie, undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Barry, Philip, 1945 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Barry, Robert J., 1955 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Bartlett, Arthur, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Bassett, Tom, 1969 December 14 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Bate, Virginia, 1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Bates, Esther Willard, 1942-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 92-95)
    - Bates, Slyvia, undated (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Beach, Stewart, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Beal, Donald, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Beals, Lawrence and Elizabeth, undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Beck, Pat, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Beebe, Dick, undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Beebe, Richard T., 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Beede, Ivan, 1923-1938, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 104-105)
    - Belin, Edmond, 1923 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Belloc, Hilaire, 1937 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Benditsky, N., 1935 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Benedict, Ruth, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Benét, Laura, 1932-1959 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Benét, Marjie, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Benét, Rosemary, undated (Box 3, Folder 112)
      to Nannette Smith
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1931-1944 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1925-1948 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Benkovitz, Miriam J., 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Benn, Ernest J. P. (Ernest John Pickstone), Sir, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Bennett, C. A., undated (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Bennett, Stanley Thomas, 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Bennington Banner, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      Includes: Resch, Tyler
    - Bennington College, 1949-1967 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Bentley, Richard, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Berger, Helen M., 1950-1967 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - The Berkshire Athenaeum, 1942-1946 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - The Berkshire Evening Eagle, 1945 April 27 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Berridge, Ruth, 1937 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Berry, John, 1960-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Berthrong, Don, 1952 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Beuf, Carlo, 1947, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Beuve-Mery, M., 1961 August 6 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Biddle, Arthur W., 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Bird, Brian and Betty, undated (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Birnbaum, Karl and Britta, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Bischoff, A., 1961 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Black Cat Press, 1936 September 8 (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Blair, Wiley Jr., 1941 (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Blegen, ----, 1965 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Bliss, Marion L, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Blitzstein, Marc, 1929 January 20 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Blood, Isobel Gardiner, undated (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Blumenthal, Joe and Ann, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Bodine, J. M., undated (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Bogan, Louise, 1929 January 11 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Bond, W. H. (William Henry), 1961-1964 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Bond Wheelwright Company Publishers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Bordus, Ayris, 1911 March 3 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Boston Public Library, 1949 March 29 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Boston City Hospital, 1964 January 3 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Bottke, Karl G. (Karl George), 1960 March 30 (Box 4, Folder 149)
      To Eunice Smith
    - Bowdoin College, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Bowen, Frances Jean, 1952 July 28 (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Bowers, Maurice, 1940 November 7 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Bozyou, Edith, undated (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Bradbury, B., undated (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1924 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Bradford, Thelma, undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Bradley, Leverett, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1925-1960 (Box 4, Folder 158-159)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1926-1973 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Brannaw, J. D., 1928 April (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Breadloaf Writers Conference, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - Bredin, Lewis Leonard, 1935-1936 (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Breuf, H., 1927 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Brevard College Library, 1939 January 4 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Bridenbaugh, Carl, 1949-1956 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Brion, Mary Louise, 1966 July 30 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - British Book Center, Inc., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Brooks, Erica May, 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1924-1950 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Brown University. Library, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Bryson, Lyman, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Brown, William, 1913 December 9 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Brunner, Elizabeth, 1968-1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Buchanan, Scott, 1947 February 18 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Bullock, Mrs., undated (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Bullock, Hugh, 1935 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Burke, John, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Burkhard, Arthur, undated (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Bushnell, Laverne, 1940 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Burt, Maxwell Struthers, 1936-1945 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Byrne, Josephine L., 1935 November 2 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - "C" General, 1919-1963 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Cady, John, 1951 October 10 (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - Cain, Mildred Palmer, 1925-19 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Calder, Alexander, 1926 December 21
    - Calhoun, Frank and Polly, 1942-1951 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - Calhoun, John E. and Marjorie, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Calkins, Earnest Elmo, 1946 August 19 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Camp Edwards, Massachusets, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Camp, Elizabeth, 1927-1939 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Canby, Henry S., 1925-1946 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Canby, Marion, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Candell, Clara and Victor, 1950 June 10 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Carleton, Phillip D., 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - Carlyle Straub Publisher, 1936 August 29 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Carman, Rose, 1943 March 2 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - Carmer, Carl, 1936-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Carmichael, R. D., 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - The Carolina Quarterly, 1958 March 27 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - Carpenter, Margaret, 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Cary, Richard, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Casadei, Marie S., 1950 February 14 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Case, Lockwood & Brainard Company, 1935 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Cassirer, Tom and Sidi, 1960-1974 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - Catamount National Bank, 1971 January 28 (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Catholic University of America, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Cattell, Elizabeth, undated (Box 5, Folder 207)
    - Catton, William Robert, 1939 December 6 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - Centre for Prehistory and Paleontology, Kenya, 1965 March 29 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - Ceneull, Sarah, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - The Century Association, 1951-1970 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - Cerf, Bennett, undated (Box 5, Folder 212)
    - Chabrier, Charles, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Chandler, John, 1968 February 12 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Chapin, Katherine Garrison, 1935 October (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - Chaplin, Dora, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Chapman, James W., 1974 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Chappell, Albert H., 1914-1939 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Chappell, George S., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Chappell, Margaret, 1940-1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Charles E. Tuttle Co. Inc, 1961 April 21 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Charles L. Rumrill & Co., 1947 October (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Charles Scribners' Sons, 1933-1964 (Box 6, Folder 223-225)
      See also: Wheelock, John Hall
    - Charleton, Arthur, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 226)
    - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1951 May 6 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Cheney, Lillian, undated (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - Chester, Betty, 1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - Chester, Colby Mitchell, 1945 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - Chien, Teng and Ann, 1959-1973 (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Chism, Murray S., 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Chisolm, Ruth A., 1935 October 14 (Box 6, Folder 233)
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1948 October 7 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - Christman, Henry and Zoe, 1937-1968 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Chubb, Thomas C., 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - The Churchman, 1923 July 23 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    - Ciardi, John, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    - Civil War Book Club, 1960, undated (Box 6, Folder 239)
    - Claremont Men's College, 1956, undated (Box 6, Folder 240)
    - Clark, Edward, 1941-1944 (Box 6, Folder 241)
    - Clark, F. North, 1946 September 4 (Box 6, Folder 242)
    - Clark, George F., 1935, undated (Box 6, Folder 243)
    - Clark H. Getts, Inc., 1945-1949 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    - Clark, John W., undated (Box 6, Folder 245)